Riley Slayden | GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn

Missoula, Montana 59823 | Willing to Relocate | 406-240-4587 | slaydenriley@gmail.com

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full stack web developer experienced in Ruby on Rails and React/Redux. With a professional background in education and music, I embrace a curiosity for how things work and a motivation to further develop my technical skills. As a proven communicator, I bring a unique perspective to the technical workforce with a keen eye for detail and a desire to help others.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, React, Redux

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Portfolio Website - GitHub | Live Site

A custom portfolio website and Content Management System (CMS) built using Ruby on Rails, React, and Redux.

- Utilized Rails sessions and cookies to safely log users in and out of the app for commenting.
- Built a CMS admin panel to manage and edit projects, posts, tags, and user accounts.
- Implemented a rich-text editor, Quill, to store posts as HTML in the database.
- Deployed to the web using Heroku and set it to a custom domain name, <u>www.rileyslayden.com</u>.

Music Market - GitHub | Video Demo

An instrument marketplace built with a vanilla Javascript frontend and a Rails API backend.

- Furthered core object oriented Javascript skills and understanding by creating a Single Page Application (SPA).
- Created a pseudo Model/View/Controller (MVC) frontend to handle views, logic, and fetch requests to the Rails API.
- Designed JSON serializers with Rails to send JSON payloads to the frontend in an organized manner.

Gigger - GitHub | Live Site | Video Demo

A gig management system for bands and venues, a place for concert go-ers to find shows.

- Designed a signup system containing 3 user types, each with unique authorizations through the gem "cancan".
- Implemented Rails partials to render similar forms on different view pages and keep code DRY.
- Integrated Omniauth to handle user authentication safely through Facebook.

EXPERIENCE

The Resort at Paws Up

Guest Services Agent and Driver.

Greenough, Montana 07/2020 - 12/31/20

- Assisted in the safe transportation of high-profile guests from the Missoula private airport to the resort.
- Acted as the first point of contact for guests and answered guestions related to the resort/assisted with check-in.
- Operated several vehicles in the fleet, including Sprinter Vans, ProMaster Vans, and various Lexus models.

National Park Radio

Fayetteville, Arkansas

05/2019 - 03/2020

Professional touring banjo player.

- Toured through 30+ states and played 60+ concerts for thousands of fans.
- Learned sound engineering utilizing modern technologies such as Behringer to help sound engineers at shows.
- Communicated with booking agents and band members to schedule tours, shows, and negotiate contracts and payments.

YMCA of Columbia-Willamette

Portland, Oregon

Grout Elementary School Site Director

01/2018 - 05/2019

- Led before and after school programs in a classroom of 26 students
- Implemented the YMCA curriculum to teach students STEM, English, and writing in an engaging manner
- Volunteered in 1st and 2nd grade classrooms to teach math and assist teachers with the grading of assignments

EDUCATION

Flatiron School (6% acceptance rate)

Online

Full stack web development, focusing on Ruby, Rails, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Redux

10/2019 - 03/2021

University of Montana / Portland State University

Missoula, MT / Portland, OR 08/2015 - 05/2018

Completed 77 credits towards a degree in Elementary Education (3.85 GPA)